The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Computational complexity
教授：计算复杂度
is basically about how hard is a problem, right?
基本上是关于问题有多难，对吧？
There are some problems that are really easy
有些问题真的很容易
and some problems that are really hard.
还有一些非常困难的问题。
And Eric drew this line on the board
埃里克在黑板上画了这条线
where you have really easy on the left
左边真的很方便
and really hard on the right.
而且真的很难在右边。
What's the hardest problem that we can possibly have?
我们可能遇到的最困难的问题是什么？
AUDIENCE: It was chess, right?
听众：是国际象棋吧？
Or something like that?
或类似的东西？
PROFESSOR: No, there's something beyond chess.
教授：不，国际象棋之外还有其他东西。
AUDIENCE: A halting problem?
听众：一个停顿的问题？
PROFESSOR: Halting problem.
教授：暂停问题。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
Halting problem is somewhere here.
暂停问题在这里。
So what's the best solution for the halting problem?
那么，解决停顿问题的最佳解决方案是什么？
Running time.
运行时间。
AUDIENCE: It is exponential, or something?
听众：是指数的，还是什么？
PROFESSOR: You'd wish.
教授：您希望。
AUDIENCE: Oh really?
听众：真的吗？
It's not even exponential?
它甚至不是指数？
AUDIENCE: I think there's like no solution.
听众：我认为没有解决办法。
PROFESSOR: There is no solution for the halting problem.
教授：没有解决暂停问题的方法。
No matter how much time, computers, and money you have,
无论您有多少时间，电脑和金钱，
you cannot solve the halting problem.
您无法解决暂停问题。
It's undesignable.
这是无法设计的。
So this is the worst kind of problem you can come up with.
因此，这是您可能遇到的最糟糕的问题。
AUDIENCE: What exactly is the halting problem?
听众：暂停问题到底是什么？
PROFESSOR: So halting problem is given
教授：因此提出了中止问题
a program in any representation that makes sense to you,
一个对您有意义的程序，
machine language, CE, assembly, parsing tree, whatever
机器语言，CE，汇编，解析树等
you want, decide if it terminates or not.
您需要确定它是否终止。
Sounds really simple, right?
听起来真的很简单，对吧？
Turns out there's a proof that says it's impossible to solve.
事实证明，有证据表明无法解决。
So you can't say will terminate or will not terminate.
因此，您不能说将终止或不会终止。
AUDIENCE: Well, but for some programs, it's like while true,
听众：是的，但是对于某些程序，这就像是真实的，
but there's no break.
但没有休息。
PROFESSOR: So Turing Machine.
教授：图灵机。
Yeah.
是的
If you have a machine where you're not allowed loops,
如果您有一台不允许循环的机器，
then it's easy to know what's going to happen.
那么很容易知道会发生什么。
So you need to have a Turing machine, something
所以你需要有一台图灵机
that allows loops.
允许循环。
So some instances are easy, right?
所以有些实例很容易，对吧？
But for the general case of you have
但是对于一般情况
to write a program that gets another program and outputs
编写获取另一个程序并输出的程序
this bit, we don't know how to do that.
这一点，我们不知道该怎么做。
But we've proven that nobody will know how to do that,
但是我们已经证明没有人会知道如何做到这一点，
so we're OK with it.
所以我们可以接受。
So this means undecidable.
因此，这意味着不确定。
We know that nobody will ever be able to solve this.
我们知道没有人能够解决这个问题。
So if you're given the halting problem on an interview,
因此，如果在面试中遇到停顿问题，
it's safe to laugh in the guy's face and tell them,
可以笑着告诉他，这是安全的
why don't you show me how to do it?
你为什么不告诉我怎么做？
So what is better than undecidable?
那么，什么比不确定还好呢？
There are these problems here that are outright impossible.
这些问题在这里是完全不可能的。
What's the next best thing?
接下来最好的是什么？
AUDIENCE: Chess?
听众：下棋？
I know chess is in there somewhere.
我知道国际象棋在那儿。
PROFESSOR: Chess is still here.
教授：国际象棋还在这里。
There's something harder than that.
有比这更难的事情。
AUDIENCE: Is it R, or something like that?
听众：是R还是类似的东西？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So this is the boundary for R and this whole thing
所以这是R和整个事物的边界
is R. What R?
是R。R是什么？
R is-- so if these are undecidable,
R是-因此，如果这些不确定，
R means decidable, right?
R代表果断吧？
So you can write an algorithm that will compute the answer
因此，您可以编写一种算法来计算答案
and do that in a finite amount of time.
并在有限的时间内做到这一点。
Will the world end before the algorithm ends?
在算法结束之前世界会终结吗？
Maybe, who knows.
也许，谁知道。
But at least there's a finite amount of time,
但是至少有有限的时间，
so the problem can be solved somehow.
因此问题可以通过某种方式解决。
That means R.
那就是R。
AUDIENCE: R is like, real, like it's not.
听众：R是真实的，而不是真实的。
PROFESSOR: Real, OK.
教授：好的，好的。
AUDIENCE: So like numbers, like, you know, real numbers--
听众：就像数字，就像实数一样，
PROFESSOR: So you know it actually comes from recursive,
教授：所以您知道它实际上来自递归，
because some old people decided that recursive
因为有些老人认为递归
means it terminates at some point.
表示它在某个时刻终止。
This is really old school stuff, 1940.
这是1940年真正的老派东西。
So R actually stands for recursive.
因此，R实际上代表递归。
Just know that R means decidable.
只需知道R表示可判定。
Weird abbreviation, but oh well.
奇怪的缩写，但是哦。
AUDIENCE: I'll go with real.
听众：我会讲真实的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
What's next?
下一步是什么？
So some problems are in R. All the ones
因此，R中存在一些问题。
that we care about are in r.
我们关心的是
So what's better than r?
那么有什么比r好呢？
R means it's going to terminate at some point,
R表示它将在某个时刻终止，
there is a running time for the problem.
该问题有运行时间。
What's the better than that?
有什么比这更好的呢？
Exponential, OK.
指数，好的。
What does exponential mean?
指数是什么意思？
AUDIENCE: Exponential?
听众：指数？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So the running time looks like what?
那么运行时间看起来像什么？
AUDIENCE: 2 to the 10, or something constant to the n?
听众：2到10，还是常数n？
2 to the n of the C?
2到C的n？
PROFESSOR: For some constant C, right?
教授：对于一些常数C，对吗？
So it's not just 2 to the n.
因此，不仅仅是n的2。
The moment you have a 2 to the n,
当您的n等于2时，
we're like, OK, if you're already
我们想，好吧，如果您已经
in this bad of a situation, I don't
在这种糟糕的情况下，我不会
care if this is a polynomial.
注意这是否是一个多项式。
I don't care if it's an n or n to the 100,
我不在乎100是n还是n
you're already pretty much screwed,
你已经被搞砸了，
you're not going to solve this before the world ends.
您不会在世界终结之前解决这个问题。
So that's what exponential means.
这就是指数的意思。
Going to solve it, but not before the world
要解决它，但不是世界
ends for most practical problems.
结束大多数实际问题。
What's better than exponential?
有什么比指数更好的？
AUDIENCE: NP.
听众：NP。
PROFESSOR: OK, and before we talk about NP,
教授：好的，在我们谈论NP之前，
let's talk about the easy case, the problems
让我们谈谈简单的情况，问题
that we've talked about all the time in the semester.
这学期我们一直在谈论。
AUDIENCE: May I ask you a stupid question?
听众：我可以问你一个愚蠢的问题吗？
What does NP stand for?
NP代表什么？
PROFESSOR: It's not a stupid question.
教授：这不是一个愚蠢的问题。
It has a really hard to answer.
这真的很难回答。
So the one-sentence answer is NP stands
所以一句话的答案是NP立场
for non deterministic binomial.
用于非确定性二项式。
And we're going to go over that at some point
我们将在某个时候解决
in the next few minutes.
在接下来的几分钟内。
OK, so what problems have we talked about?
好，那么我们在谈论什么问题呢？
All the terms, except for one problem,
所有条款，除了一个问题，
for the knapsack problem, the entire term
对于背包问题，整个学期
we talked about some sort of problems.
我们谈到了一些问题。
Polynomial.
多项式
These are the reasonably easy ones.
这些是相当容易的。
So polynomial problems are those where t of n is n to the C,
所以多项式问题是那些n的t是C的n，
so it's a binomial.
所以这是一个二项式
The running time is a binomial in terms of the input sites.
就输入站点而言，运行时间是二项式的。
Why does this matter?
为什么这么重要？
If you have a polynomial algorithm,
如果您有多项式算法，
than if you double the input, then the running time
而不是如果您将输入加倍，那么运行时间
is going to be 2 to the C times n to the C.
是C的2乘以C的n。
So every time you double the input,
因此，每次您将输入翻倍时，
the running time will increase by a constant factor.
运行时间将增加一个常数。
And you know what that is.
你知道那是什么。
If your problem is exponential, then if you double the input,
如果您的问题是指数级的，那么如果您将输入倍增，
then the running time increases quadratically.
然后运行时间将增加两倍。
It's not a linear increase.
这不是线性增长。
Here it's a linear increase.
这是线性增加。
The factor isn't 2, but it's still a linear increase.
该因子不是2，但仍是线性增加。
Make sense?
说得通？
So that's why we like these problems, at least
这就是为什么我们至少喜欢这些问题的原因
we like them more than anything else.
我们最喜欢它们。
So polynomial problems are the nice and easy ones
所以多项式问题是很好的和容易的问题
that we've talked about so far.
到目前为止我们已经讨论过。
What does NP stand for?
NP代表什么？
Give me a practical definition.
给我一个实际的定义。
AUDIENCE: You can check it [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您可以检查它[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so NP means that we can write the verifier.
教授：好的，所以NP表示我们可以编写验证程序。
I'm going to say exactly what you said with different words.
我要用不同的话确切地说出你说的话。
That takes a solution to the problem.
这就解决了这个问题。
And of course, it has to think the input to the problem
当然，它必须考虑问题的输入
and tells us is it correct or is it not correct.
并告诉我们是正确还是不正确。
And this very fire is NP.
而这就是NP。
So the very fire runs in polynomial time.
因此，非常之火在多项式时间内运行。
Yes.
是。
So if the verifier runs in polynomial time,
因此，如果验证程序以多项式时间运行，
what's the solution size and what's the input size?
解决方案的大小是多少，输入的大小是多少？
AUDIENCE: I think the-- I mean, the solution said it's like 01,
听众：我想-我的意思是，解决方案说它像01，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: If we have decision problems.
教授：如果我们有决策问题。
An algorithm that solves an NP problem.
解决NP问题的算法。
If you run it against the verifier,
如果您针对验证程序运行它，
also has to convince you that its answer is correct.
还必须说服您它的答案是正确的。
So the problems that we talked about in class
所以我们在课堂上讨论的问题
were decidability problems where you have to say,
是不得不说的可决定性问题，
is it possible to do this?
是否有可能做到这一点？
Yes or no.
是还是不是。
When you have a verifier with you,
当您有验证者时，
then you have to output a string that convinces the verifier
那么您必须输出一个可以说服验证者的字符串
that your answer is correct.
你的答案是正确的。
So like if you have a problem that
因此，如果您遇到问题
says-- if you have three sets, for example-- that says,
说-例如，如果您有三套-
given a logical expression, can you assign variable values such
给定一个逻辑表达式，您可以分配变量值吗
that the expression is true?
这个表达是真的吗？
If I say yes, what does that mean?
如果我同意，那是什么意思？
That means nothing.
那没什么。
How do I convince you that my answer is correct?
我如何说服您我的答案是正确的？
I will have to give you the assignment, right?
我必须给你任务，对不对？
And then you can verify in polynomial time
然后可以验证多项式时间
if my answer is right or not.
如果我的答案正确与否。
So the input to the verifier, this solution,
因此，验证者的输入，此解决方案，
is not necessarily the decision.
不一定是决定。
It's not just the bit, yes or no.
不只是一点点，是或否。
So if the verifier runs in polynomial time,
因此，如果验证程序以多项式时间运行，
what's true about the problem input
问题输入的真实情况是什么
and what's true about the problem output which
问题输出到底是什么
becomes an input to the verifier?
成为验证者的输入？
They have to be polynomial in size.
它们的大小必须是多项式。
Otherwise, my algorithm wouldn't be
否则，我的算法就不会
able to consume them fast enough.
能够足够快地消耗它们。
So actually, polynomial means that the running time
所以实际上，多项式意味着运行时间
is polynomial in the input size.
是输入大小的多项式。
So the input size is automatically all set.
因此，输入大小会自动全部设置。
But the solution has to be polynomial in the input size
但是解决方案必须是输入大小的多项式
as well.
也一样
And if you're thinking decision problems,
如果您在思考决策问题，
you can be more rigorous and call this a proof.
您可以更加严格，并将其称为证明。
So if this proof is binomial in the input size,
因此，如果此证明在输入大小上是二项式的，
then if I'm really, really lucky,
如果我真的很幸运
I can take the input to a problem,
我可以输入一个问题，
and I can flip coins and use the corn results as bits,
我可以掷硬币并将玉米结果用作碎屑，
and put them together, and create the proof.
并将它们放在一起，并创建证明。
If I'm really, really lucky, I'll get the right proof.
如果我真的真的很幸运，我将获得正确的证明。
Chances of that happening almost zero,
发生这种情况的几率几乎为零，
but if I'm really, really lucky, conceptually I can get a proof.
但是如果我真的很幸运，从概念上讲我可以得到证明。
This is what a non-deterministic polynomial means.
这就是非确定性多项式的含义。
It means that if you have a magical machine where
这意味着如果您有一台神奇的机器，
you can flip a coin, and it will always be lucky,
您可以掷硬币，这将永远是幸运的，
then you can output the proof in polynomial time.
然后您可以输出多项式时间的证明。
So far so good?
到现在为止还挺好？
So this definition of a machine that can flip random bits
因此，对可以翻转随机位的机器的定义
is really useful, because we can use it to build a common sense
真的很有用，因为我们可以用它来建立常识
proof that P is not NP.
证明P不是NP。
There is no real rigorous math proof that P's not NP.
没有真正严格的数学证明P不是NP。
That's worth a million dollars.
值一百万美元。
There is no proof that P equals NP.
没有证据表明P等于NP。
If you have proof that P equals NP, then
如果您有证明P等于NP，那么
that's worth a lot more.
这值得更多。
And I will use that in the common sense proof
我将在常识证明中使用它
that I'm going to show you now.
我现在要告诉你。
So we don't know if P is NP-- get it right-- if P is NP
所以我们不知道P是否为NP-正确-P是否为NP
or if P is not NP.
或者如果P不是NP。
This is an open problem, and there's at least $1 million
这是一个悬而未决的问题，至少有100万美元
worth of prize money for it.
值得的奖金。
Let's talk about an algorithm where
让我们谈谈一种算法
if you would know-- so if you would
如果您知道-如果您愿意
be able to solve NP problems in polynomial time,
能够在多项式时间内解决NP问题，
you would be able to make a lot of money.
您将能够赚很多钱。
A million dollars is nothing compared
一百万美元可算不上什么
to what you could make if you could do that.
如果可以做到的话
So I'm going to use that to convince you
所以我要用它说服你
that nobody knows how to solve NP problems in P time.
没有人知道如何在P时间内解决NP问题。
Suppose you want to do something really bad.
假设您想做一些非常糟糕的事情。
Suppose you want to impersonate a bank.
假设您要模拟一个银行。
So you guys probably imagine that banks nowadays
所以你们可能会想像现在的银行
don't transfer money to each other
不要互相转移钱
by sending trucks with gold bars.
通过发送带有金条的卡车。
They do that every once in awhile, but most of the time
他们偶尔会这样做，但是大多数时候
the transfers happen very quickly over the internet.
互联网上的转移非常迅速。
So banks have a secure connection,
因此银行之间建立了安全的连接，
and they say, yo, give me a billion dollars.
他们说，哟，给我十亿美元。
I'll give it back to you in a few days.
过几天我会把它还给你。
Sure.
当然。
Done deal.
木已成舟。
Now imagine what you could do if you
现在想象一下，如果您能做些什么
could impersonate one of those banks.
可能冒充其中一家银行。
Sweet happy life in some faraway place, right?
在遥远的地方过着幸福的生活吧？
What would it take to impersonate another bank?
冒充另一家银行会怎样？
It turns out that the encryption algorithm that
原来，加密算法
use to secure this links is an algorithm called RSA.
用于保护此链接的安全性是一种称为RSA的算法。
Do you guys remember that?
你们还记得吗？
Heard about it?
听说了？
So in RSA, each party-- so each bank
在RSA中，每一方-每家银行
has a secret key that consists of two numbers--
有一个由两个数字组成的密钥-
P and Q-- big prime numbers.
P和Q-大质数。
And say each of these are N-bit prime numbers.
并说每个都是N位素数。
And then they have a probably key.
然后他们有一个大概的钥匙。
So they have a number that announce
所以他们有一个数字宣布
that is N equals P times Q. So this
那是N等于P乘以Q。所以这
is announced to the entire world.
已向全世界宣布。
This is public.
这是公开的。
We went through this [INAUDIBLE] set, right?
我们经历了这个[听不清]，对吗？
So this rings a bell.
所以这响了。
They have to announce this so that the other people can
他们必须宣布这一点，以便其他人可以
encrypt messages for them.
为他们加密消息。
If you want someone else to be able to send you a message,
如果您希望其他人能够向您发送消息，
you have to tell them your n.
你必须告诉他们你的n。
Now if you know P and Q, you can decrypt messages.
现在，如果您知道P和Q，就可以解密消息。
So you can pretend you're the bank.
这样您就可以假装自己是银行。
Now let's set up a problem in this way.
现在让我们以这种方式设置一个问题。
Given a verifier that does long division--
假设验证者可以进行长期除法-
so we have a verifier that the verifiers input is N,
因此我们有一个验证者，验证者输入为N，
and some guess P, P guess, right?
还有一些猜P，P猜对吧？
So the verifier will compute N modulo P.
因此，验证者将计算N个模P。
And if N modulo P is 0, then it will say happy.
如果N模P为0，则表示高兴。
Actually, it will say, you're rich as hell.
实际上，它会说，你很富有。
If it's not 0, then well, tough luck, try again.
如果不是0，那么好运，再试一次。
So if you could make this verifier happy,
因此，如果您可以使验证者满意，
you could get P. So given public information,
您可以获得P。因此，鉴于公开信息，
you could get the private information that
您可以获得私人信息，
would allow you to impersonate the bank.
可以让您冒充银行。
This is called a factoring problem by the way.
顺带一提，这称为保理问题。
So P and N are usually 1024 bits.
因此，P和N通常为1024位。
So the chances of doing that with a coin flip, no.
因此，通过抛硬币来实现这一目标的机会不行。
The chances of guessing it are one in two to the 1024--
猜出来的几率是1024的二分之一
it's basically worse than having to pick
基本上比必须挑选要差
a random atom in the universe and choosing the right one.
宇宙中的一个随机原子并选择正确的原子。
So not going to happen.
所以不会发生。
But if you had an algorithm that takes a verifier
但是如果您有采用验证程序的算法
and produces an input that makes it happy,
并产生使它高兴的输入，
then you would solve this problem,
那么你会解决这个问题，
and you would impersonate the bank,
你会冒充银行
and you would become really rich,
你会变得很富有
and then the whole world's economic system
然后是整个世界的经济体系
would be in a terrible situation.
情况会很糟糕。
AUDIENCE: P and Q are primes, right?
听众：P和Q是素数，对吗？
So couldn't you just find all the primes?
那么，您难道不就找到所有素数吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, so look at it from this perspective,
教授：好吧，所以从这个角度来看，
the economic system still functions.
经济体系仍然运转。
It's not like everyone's money disappeared somewhere.
并不是每个人的钱都消失在某个地方。
Therefore, nobody was able to pull this off.
因此，没有人能够做到这一点。
AUDIENCE: Isn't there a quantum algorithm to do it
听众：没有量子算法可以做到这一点
or that's something different?
还是有些不同？
PROFESSOR: So this assumes Turing machines.
教授：所以这里假设使用图灵机。
We're assuming regular Turing machines.
我们假设使用普通的图灵机。
A quantum computer breaks that abstraction.
量子计算机打破了这种抽象。
For practical purposes, if you had a quantum computer
出于实际目的，如果您有一台量子计算机
that can manipulate this many bits.
可以操纵这么多位。
Then you would break RSA, and the world would go to hell.
然后，您将破坏RSA，世界将走向地狱。
So hopefully by the time quantum computers get this powerful,
因此，希望在量子计算机变得强大之前，
we'll invent new security algorithms that replace them.
我们将发明替代它们的新安全算法。
But the fact that eCommerce works now and that banks work
但是事实是，电子商务现在可以工作，银行也可以工作
means that nobody is able to solve
意味着没有人能够解决
NP problems in polynomial time.
多项式时间内的NP问题。
So by the way, factoring is not the hardest type of NP problem.
因此，顺便说一下，保理不是NP问题中最难的类型。
Factoring is somewhere here.
保理在这里。
OK.
好。
Any questions about this part?
对这部分有任何疑问吗？
AUDIENCE: So factoring is not an NP problem?
听众：那么保理不是NP问题？
PROFESSOR: Factoring is NP, but it's not
教授：保理是NP，但不是
the most difficult type of NP problem.
NP问题中最困难的类型。
We'll get to those right now.
我们现在就解决这些。
So this is a common sense proof not the math proof
所以这是常识证明，不是数学证明
that NP is not P-- that at least nobody
NP不是P-至少没有人
knows how to solve NP problems in polynomial time.
知道如何在多项式时间内解决NP问题。
So there are these NP problems that if you think about it,
因此，存在这些NP问题，如果您考虑一下，
the solution is polynomial in size.
解的大小是多项式。
We can write a verifier in polynomial time.
我们可以用多项式时间编写一个验证器。
So why can't we write the solver in polynomial time?
那么为什么我们不能在多项式时间内编写求解器呢？
If you're a very high picture guy like managerial type,
如果您是像管理型这样的高素质人士，
then you might think, yeah why, can't you guys
那你可能会想，是的，为什么不能
just figure this out?
才知道这个吗？
Like come up with an algorithm.
喜欢想出一种算法。
Isn't that what you guys do?
你们不是吗？
Well, so theory people have been thinking
好吧，所以理论上人们一直在思考
about this for 40 years or more.
大约40年或更长时间。
So what do you do when you think about something
所以当你想到某事时你会怎么做
and you can't come up with a solution?
而您无法提出解决方案？
AUDIENCE: Say it's impossible?
听众：说不可能吗？
PROFESSOR: You try to say that it's impossible.
教授：您试图说这是不可能的。
So you try to prove that P is not NP.
因此，您尝试证明P不是NP。
But if you fail to do that too, what do you do next?
但是，如果您同样也做不到，那么下一步该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Offer a million dollars
观众：出价一百万美元
to someone who can do it.
给可以做到的人。
PROFESSOR: That too.
教授：那也是。
That might help.
这可能会有所帮助。
Well, you complain that it's really, really hard, right?
好吧，你抱怨这真的非常非常难，对吧？
You want to go back to your boss or you
您想回去老板还是您
want to go back to the world, and say, we thought about this.
想回到世界，说，我们考虑了这一点。
It is true that with thought about it for four years,
的确，经过四年的思考，
but it's a really, really hard problem.
但这是一个非常非常困难的问题。
Well, so for undecidable problems--
好吧，对于不确定的问题，
so for the whole thing problems, they
所以对于整个问题，他们
are able to convince the world that nobody can solve this,
能够说服世界，没有人能解决这个问题，
so we're all good.
所以我们都很好。
So we couldn't come up with a solution, because nobody can.
因此我们无法提出解决方案，因为没有人可以。
Here, we can't prove that P is not NP yet.
在这里，我们不能证明P还不是NP。
So instead the next best thing that theory people
因此，理论上人们的第二件事就是
could come up with is-- they saw,
他们可以想到的是，
what are the hardest kind of NP problems?
NP问题最难解决的是什么？
Let's look at them and let's see if we can solve them
让我们看一下，看看是否可以解决它们
in some way.
某种程度上来说。
And they found some problems here
他们在这里发现了一些问题
that are the hardest NP problems.
那是最难的NP问题。
And they called them NP-complete problems.
他们称它们为NP完全问题。
And we'll see why complete in a bit.
我们将稍后解释为什么要完成。
So these are the hardest NP problems that you can have.
因此，这些是您可能遇到的最困难的NP问题。
Factoring is not one of them.
保理不是其中之一。
Factoring is not with the cool kids,
不适合酷孩子的因素，
even though it would make you rich.
即使这会让你变得富有。
There are some problems that are harder than that.
有些问题比这更难。
OK so for these NP-complete problems,
好的，对于这些NP完全问题，
turns out there are a few hundred of them that
原来有几百个
would have practical implications.
有实际意义。
So you wouldn't be able to get rich right away,
因此，您将无法马上致富，
but still you'd be able to solved the important problems
但您仍然可以解决重要问题
that would save companies a lot of money.
这样可以为公司节省很多钱。
So you think, if there's a solution
所以你认为，如果有解决方案
someone would come up with it.
有人会想出来的。
It also turns out that they're all interrelated.
事实证明，它们都是相互关联的。
So if you can solve one problem, you can solve all of them.
因此，如果您可以解决一个问题，则可以解决所有问题。
And you do that through reductions,
然后通过减少来实现
which we'll go over in a bit.
我们稍后再讨论。
But the bottom line is there are hundreds
但最重要的是有数百个
of NP-complete problems.
NP完全问题。
And if you solve one, then you solved everything.
如果您解决了一个问题，那么您就解决了所有问题。
For now theory people are trying to say,
目前，人们正在试图说理论，
look there are all these problems.
看起来有所有这些问题。
If anyone would solve any of them, all of them
如果有人能解决任何一个，所有的
would go away.
会消失。
Nobody was able to solve any of them,
没有人能够解决任何一个问题，
so they must be really, really hard.
因此他们必须非常非常努力。
This is the best they could come up with.
这是他们能想到的最好的方法。
This is NP complete.
这是NP完成的。
AUDIENCE: This is same lecture that you-- any problem that's
听众：这是您的同一个讲座-任何问题
already [INAUDIBLE] transform it into a different problem?
已经[音频不清晰]将其转换为其他问题？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So if you have the solution for one of them,
因此，如果您有其中一种解决方案，
you could transform all the other ones into that problem
你可以把其他所有的都变成那个问题
just like we do with graph transformations,
就像我们对图形进行转换一样
solve it, use the solution for it to solve all the other ones.
解决它，使用解决方案解决所有其他问题。
So if anyone could solve any of those hundreds of problems,
因此，如果任何人都可以解决这数百个问题中的任何一个，
we'd have the solution to all of them in an instant.
我们会立即解决所有问题。
The fact that we don't have a solution to them
我们没有解决方案的事实
means that nobody was able to solve any of them.
意味着没有人能够解决其中任何一个。
AUDIENCE: Like there are some problems like the chess problem
听众：像国际象棋一样，有些问题
that can be solved exponential time.
可以解决指数时间。
PROFESSOR: Those are different.
教授：那是不同的。
Chess is here.
国际象棋在这里。
AUDIENCE: So we can solve chess though, right?
观众：所以我们可以解决国际象棋，对吗？
It's just exponential time.
这只是指数时间。
Right?
对？
PROFESSOR: As far as I know, because it's exponential time,
教授：据我所知，因为这是指数时间，
there's no algorithm that can actually
没有算法可以实际
look at the entire configuration space, and tell if you can win
查看整个配置空间，并告诉您是否可以赢
or not.
或不。
So solving chess, what's chess?
那么解决棋，什么是棋？
Chess has given a board.
国际象棋给董事会了。
Can I win or not from this board?
我可以从这个委员会中赢吗？
This would be very useful in playing chess,
这在下棋时非常有用，
because you start with the initial board,
因为您从最初的董事会开始，
and then for every move you can make,
然后您可以采取的任何行动，
you look at the resulting board, and you
你看一下结果板，你
say can I win or not from that board.
说我可以从那个董事会赢还是不能赢。
If you're in a board configuration in which you
如果您使用的板配置中
can win, you don't want to go to a configuration
可以赢，你不想去配置
where you won't be able to win anymore.
在这里你将不再能赢。
So if you keep doing this you eventually win.
因此，如果继续这样做，您最终会获胜。
So it would be really nice to have this algorithm.
因此，拥有此算法真的很好。
Yeah, we don't have it.
是的，我们没有。
We don't have it and chess is unsolved.
我们没有它，而象棋尚未解决。
Wait.
等待。
AUDIENCE: So only things that are below P--
听众：所以只有P以下的东西-
but there are some algorithms that run in exponential time.
但是有些算法会以指数形式运行。
They just take longer.
他们只需要更长的时间。
PROFESSOR: So the problem is what's the input size?
教授：那么问题是输入大小是多少？
Exponential in what?
指数在什么？
If it's going to be-- if the running time is 2 to the n,
如果是这样-如果运行时间是2到n，
and it's 10, then that's fine.
那是10，那很好。
But for chess its exponential in the board configuration.
但是对于国际象棋来说，它在棋盘配置中是指数的。
And it turns out that there's so many board configurations
事实证明，电路板配置太多
that we don't have computers fast
我们没有快速的计算机
enough to solve the whole thing.
足以解决整个问题。
So deep blue goes to a level-- to a depth
所以深蓝色达到一个层次
I think of somewhere around 15 and can barely competes
我认为大约15岁左右，几乎无法竞争
with humans, but it's not guaranteed to win all the time.
与人类合作，但并不能保证始终赢得胜利。
So we don't have something that has completely solved chess.
因此，我们没有完全解决国际象棋的问题。
AUDIENCE: So we can only solve things below P then.
听众：那么我们只能解决P以下的问题。
PROFESSOR: We can only solve things below P
教授：我们只能解决P以下的问题
fast, reasonably fast.
快速，相当快。
So what we care about in this class
所以我们在这堂课上关心的是
is how do our algorithm scale.
我们的算法如何扩展。
So do we have this or not?
那我们有没有？
Does your algorithm scale or not?
您的算法是否可扩展？
The reason we don't like algorithms that are after this
我们不喜欢此后的算法的原因
is that for problem sizes that are really small like 8, 10,
是对于很小的问题，例如8、10
or something small, they're going to work.
或小东西，他们会工作。
But the moment the problem gets bigger and bigger,
但是当问题变得越来越严重时，
you're going to run into a dead end.
您将陷入困境。
AUDIENCE: Well, can you use DP on chess?
听众：好吧，你可以在国际象棋上使用DP吗？
PROFESSOR: You can use DP until you
教授：您可以使用DP，直到您
get to an exponential algorithm.
进入指数算法。
You might get to an exponential algorithm
您可能会遇到指数算法
where the exponent is better.
指数更好的地方。
So far all the smart algorithms for chess
到目前为止，所有国际象棋的智能算法
have reduced the c here, but they
在这里减少了c，但是他们
haven't been able to get away from 2 to the n part.
一直未能摆脱2到n部分。
If you make c smaller, sure it's going to run faster,
如果您减小c的大小，请确保它会运行得更快，
and you can explore a bigger part of the board.
您可以探索董事会的更大部分。
But you're still not going to be able to run
但是您仍然无法运行
through the whole thing before the world ends.
在世界终结之前经历整个事情。
That's a good thing to think about.
这是一件好事。
Will we solve chess before the world
我们会在世界面前解围棋吗
ends with the current algorithms and machines?
以当前的算法和机器结束？
No.
没有。
AUDIENCE: I guess.
听众：我猜。
Remember the Rubik's cube?
还记得魔方吗？
Wasn't that bordering exponential or something?
那不是指数级的东西吗？
I think Eric said that there is order one solution where
我认为Eric说有一种解决方案
the constant factor is really high.
常数因子确实很高。
So that's different.
所以不一样。
raises I think Tetris is here, but the Rubik's cube--
提出我认为俄罗斯方块在这里，但是魔方-
AUDIENCE: It's in the P, isn't it?
听众：在P中，不是吗？
Yeah.
是的
PROFESSOR: There's a solution that's
教授：有一个解决方案是
order one with a high constant [INAUDIBLE].
用高常数[音频不清晰]订购一个。
AUDIENCE: But our brains can play chess.
听众：但是我们的大脑可以下棋。
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
Our brains--
我们的大脑
AUDIENCE: We can play chess.
听众：我们可以下棋。
PROFESSOR: Well, we can play reasonably well,
教授：好吧，我们可以打得很好，
but if someone could play optimally,
但是如果有人可以发挥出最佳状态，
they'd probably beat you.
他们可能会打败你。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Can someone play optimally?
听众：有人可以发挥最佳状态吗？
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
AUDIENCE: What about machine learning?
听众：机器学习怎么样？
PROFESSOR: Machine learning problems are usually here.
教授：机器学习问题通常在这里。
That's why they don't scale, and that's
这就是为什么他们不扩大规模，这就是
why we've seen a lot of interesting machine learning,
为什么我们看到了很多有趣的机器学习，
but so far I can't talk to my computer right.
但到目前为止，我无法与计算机通话。
They can't make a lot of progress,
他们无法取得很大进步，
because they have these really hard problems that they're
因为他们有这些非常棘手的问题
working on.
正在努力。
AUDIENCE: There's Siri, right.
听众：是Siri，对。
You can talk to Siri.
您可以与Siri交谈。
PROFESSOR: Yeah OK.
教授：好的。
Sure.
当然。
I think I've seen on the Internet
我想我在互联网上看过
that it says some awful things sometimes.
有时会说一些可怕的事情。
So I wouldn't consider that solved.
所以我不会认为解决了。
So what does NP mean to us like practical terms?
那么，NP对我们来说像实际术语意味着什么？
Here's how I see it, you're on an exam or in an interview,
我是这样看的，您正在考试或面试中，
you start out with a problem.
你开始有问题。
Suppose all the possible problems
假设所有可能的问题
are a graph, because we work with graphs.
是图，因为我们使用图。
You have your starting problem.
你有开始的问题。
This Is the problem that you're trying to solve now.
这就是您现在要解决的问题。
Then you have a few destination nodes.
然后，您有几个目标节点。
Say you have merge sort.
假设您有合并排序。
We know how to solve.
我们知道如何解决。
If you can reduce your problem to merge sort,
如果您可以减少合并排序的问题，
then you're in a good position.
那你的位置就好
You're writing your solution.
您正在编写解决方案。
You're out of the room.
你不在房间里
If you can reduce your problem to a graph search algorithm,
如果您可以将问题简化为图搜索算法，
so to BFS or DFS, you're done.
这样就可以完成BFS或DFS。
If you can reduce it to shortest path, you're happy.
如果您可以将其减少到最短路径，那么您会很高兴。
You're done.
你完成了。
If you can reduce it to a dynamic programming problem
如果可以将其简化为动态编程问题
that we understand, you're done.
据我们了解，您已完成。
If you can somehow use hashing or use divide and conquer
如果可以以某种方式使用哈希或使用分而治之
with an algorithm that we studied, you're also happy.
使用我们研究过的算法，您也很高兴。
So we have all these destination points.
因此，我们拥有所有这些目的地。
And what you're trying to do is you're
而你想要做的就是
trying to get from here all the way to here via reductions.
试图通过减少从一路到达这里。
So suppose you see three reductions
所以假设您看到三个减少
that you could possibly do.
你可能会做的。
You don't have time to work on all three of them,
您没有时间去做这三个方面的工作，
so let's say you choose the middle one,
假设您选择中间一个，
because this one seems like it's the easiest one.
因为这似乎是最简单的一种。
So I'm going to guess that this is
所以我猜这是
the easiest one I can tackle.
我可以解决的最简单的方法。
So now I'm going to work on this.
所以现在我将对此进行研究。
I'm going to put the original problem aside.
我将原始问题放在一边。
And I'm going to say if I can solve this, then I'm happy.
我要说的是如果我能解决这个问题，那我会很高兴。
Now say this turns into three more reductions.
现在说这变成了另外三个减少。
And this one looks promising.
这个看起来很有希望。
it's a hard problem.
这是一个很难的问题。
You have to do a few reductions.
您必须做一些减少。
It doesn't work right away.
立即无法正常工作。
But say I take this one which looks promising,
但是我说这是一个很有前途的，
and I'm able to reduce it to a happy problem.
我可以将其简化为一个快乐的问题。
Reduction, reduction, reduction.
减少，减少，减少。
I write this up.
我写下来。
I'm done.
我受够了。
Exam solved or interview question solved.
考试解决或面试问题解决。
Now the problem is what if instead
现在的问题是，如果相反
of going on this path which is reasonably happy, what if I
走在这条相当幸福的道路上，如果我
go on a path that looks like this?
走在看起来像这样的道路上？
All the reductions that I can see from there
我从那里可以看到的所有减少
go really, really far away from the problems
真正远离问题
that I know how to solve.
我知道如何解决。
Well you're going to try some reductions,
好吧，您将尝试一些减少，
and eventually you're going to run out of time.
最终您会用光时间。
And this other interviewer is going to say, yeah,
另一个面试官会说，是的，
do you have any questions about us?
您对我们有任何疑问吗？
Or the exam people will be like, hey, can we have the exam back?
否则考试的人会像，嘿，我们可以再参加考试吗？
We want to go home now.
我们现在要回家。
So this is a bad outcome.
因此，这是一个糟糕的结果。
Up until now, all you had was good destination points.
到目前为止，您所拥有的只是不错的目的地。
So this is where you want to reach.
因此，这是您想要到达的地方。
Now we have these NP-complete problems that we know are hard.
现在，我们遇到了这些很难解决的NP问题。
I've convinced you hopefully that their hard.
我希望您相信他们的辛苦。
So if you know some NP-complete problems,
因此，如果您知道一些NP完全问题，
you also have some landmines.
你也有一些地雷。
You have some places where if you got there
你有一些地方，如果你在那里
via reductions, not a good path.
通过减少，不是一个好方法。
You want to backtrack and think of something else.
您想回溯并想到其他事情。
So for example if this was an NP-complete problem
例如，如果这是一个NP完全问题
like if this reduction then was, oh yeah,
好像减少了，是的，哦，是的，
solve [INAUDIBLE] in polynomial time.
在多项式时间内求解[音频不清晰]。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
I don't know how to do that.
我不知道该怎么做。
The world tried really hard.
世界真的很努力。
Maybe I shouldn't try this avenue on the exam.
也许我不应该在考试中尝试这种方法。
So if you know that this is NP-complete.
因此，如果您知道这是NP完全的。
You stop right there.
你就停在那里。
You don't waste anymore time.
您不再浪费时间。
So this isn't time wasted.
因此，这不会浪费时间。
If you understand NP-complete, and you read the CLRS chapter
如果您了解NP-complete，并阅读了CLRS章节
on NP-complete problems.
关于NP完全问题。
Then you also have some sad faces here.
然后，您在这里也有一些悲伤的面孔。
You have some land mines and you know not to go there.
您有一些地雷，并且知道不去那里。
So now your space that you're looking through
现在，您正在浏览的空间
is a lot more bonded.
更加粘合。
Hopefully, you're going to have better chances of finding
希望您将有更多的机会找到
a happy path, because not only you have some destinations,
一条快乐的道路，因为不仅您有一些目的地，
but you have some places that you know you shouldn't go to.
但您有一些您不应该去的地方。
So this is the point of NP-complete.
因此，这就是NP完全的要点。
You're probably really busy at the end of the term
学期末你可能真的很忙
as we all are, so I'm guessing you're not
就像我们所有人一样，所以我猜你不是
going to have time to read CLRS beyond what we really
我们将有时间阅读CLRS，超出我们真正的理解范围
ask you to read now.
请您现在阅读。
But after you're done, do yourself a favor.
但是，完成之后，请帮自己一个忙。
For the sake of your future interviews
为了将来的面试
and general happy programming life,
和一般的快乐编程生活，
read the NP-complete chapter in CLRS.
阅读CLRS中的NP完整章节。
Read the problem statements and understand them.
阅读问题陈述并理解它们。
Don't worry about the proofs.
不用担心证明。
Don't worry about the reductions that say their NP-complete.
不用担心表示NP完整的减少。
Read the statements.
阅读声明。
Believe CLRS that it's NP-complete.
相信CLRS是NP完整的。
And remember that whenever you solve a problem,
请记住，每当您解决问题时，
you want to stay away from those.
您想远离那些。
So those will be your landmines.
因此，这些将成为您的地雷。
Those will be your sad spots.
那将是您的难过之处。
Guaranteed, after you do that, your interviews
这样做之后，可以保证您的采访
will go a lot better, because you'll
会好很多，因为你会
be faster at solving problems.
更快地解决问题。
And that's what we really care about.
这就是我们真正关心的。
So that's why NP-complete is relevant in real life.
这就是为什么NP-complete与现实生活息息相关。
It gives us these data points.
它给了我们这些数据点。
Makes sense?
说得通？
All right, I want to talk about one NP complete problem that's
好吧，我想谈一个NP完全问题
really important.
真的很重要
And that is SAT.
那就是SAT。
So SAT means satisfiability.
因此，SAT意味着可满足性。
So given the logical expression, find some values
所以给定逻辑表达式，找到一些值
for the variables that make it true.
对于使它成立的变量。
Let me grab an example from here.
让我从这里举一个例子。
So in SAT your expressions come out
因此，在SAT中您的表情会出来
in a really nice form, so parsing isn't a big deal.
以一种非常好的形式，因此解析不是什么大问题。
The way they come out is there a bunch
他们出来的方式是一堆
of terms separated by AND.
用AND分隔的术语。
So your expressions look like this-- and,
所以您的表情看起来像这样-并且，
and, and-- say we have four terms.
还有-说我们有四个术语。
These look good.
这些看起来不错。
So you have some terms, say n terms,
所以您有一些条件，例如n个条件，
and they're all separated by ANDs.
并且它们都被AND隔开。
This is a term.
这是一个术语。
In a term you have variables separated by ORs.
在一个术语中，您有用OR分隔的变量。
Nothing else.
没有其他的。
Just either the variable or a variable
只是变量或变量
with a NOT in front of it.
前面有一个NOT。
So say x1 OR NOT x2, NOT x1 OR x4, NOT x3 or x4, and X2 OR X4.
因此说x1或非x2，非x1或x4，非x3或x4以及X2或X4。
So this is called the Conjuntive Normal Form, CNF.
因此，这称为合取范式CNF。
The reason this is really nice to work with is-- OK,
确实很好用的原因是-好吧，
you just have some variables here.
您这里只有一些变量。
You know that these are all joined by AND,
您知道这些都是由AND联接的，
so you're going to have to make all these terms true.
因此您必须使所有这些术语正确。
And then you have ORs inside.
然后，您在内部具有OR。
So you know that for every term, at least one
所以你知道每个学期至少有一个
of the things inside the term has to be true.
该术语中的某些事物必须是正确的。
And that's it.
就是这样。
This is the problem.
这就是问题。
This is SAT.
这是SAT。
You have n terms.
您有n个条件。
And then the number of variables that you have inside is k.
然后，您内部拥有的变量数为k。
So you have at most k variables in a term.
因此，一个学期中最多有k个变量。
This k looks like a constant factor.
这个k看起来像一个常数因子。
But it's so important that in fact it
但这很重要，实际上
shows up in the name of the problem.
以问题的名称出现。
The problem is called k-SAT.
这个问题称为k-SAT。
And there are two values of k for which
有两个k值
the problem is important.
这个问题很重要。
There's 2-SAT, and there's 3-SAT.
有2-SAT，有3-SAT。
2-SAT is polynomial.
2-SAT是多项式。
We have a solution that runs in order and time in fact.
实际上，我们有一个按顺序运行的解决方案。
Really good.
真的很好
AUDIENCE: But you're saying that to make--
听众：但是你是说要-
you're actually rearranging things or you're just--
您实际上是在重新整理东西，或者只是-
PROFESSOR: So I have to come up with values for x1, x2, x3,
教授：所以我必须拿出x1，x2，x3，
and four, so that the whole thing is true.
还有四个，所以整个事情都是对的。
And the expression is already arranged
表达式已经安排好了
in this nice form for you.
以这种适合您的形式。
AUDIENCE: It's just-- it seems like order
观众：只是-好像是命令
and, because you're just evaluating to block, right?
而且，因为您只是在评估要阻止，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Well, no, you have to come up with the values.
教授：嗯，不，您必须提出价值观。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I know.
听众：哦，我知道。
I know.
我知道。
But like--
但是就像-
PROFESSOR: OK and this seems really easy, right?
教授：好的，这似乎很容易，对吗？
Well, wait for it.
好吧，等一下。
Wait for it.
等一下
2-SAT is polynomial.
2-SAT是多项式。
3-SAT is NP-complete.
3-SAT是NP完全的。
So if you solve it, you're in turn for a Turing reward,
因此，如果您解决了问题，您将获得图灵奖励，
or you can become really, really rich.
否则你可以变得非常富有。
So n-SAT can be reduced to 3-SAT.
因此，n-SAT可以简化为3-SAT。
So for anything bigger than three,
所以对于大于三的任何东西，
n-SAT can be reduced to 3-SAT using reasonable reduction.
可以使用合理的缩减将n-SAT缩减为3-SAT。
So the input size won't explode too much.
因此，输入大小不会爆炸太多。
So why is this important.
那么为什么这很重要。
This basically shows us that 3-SAT is NP-complete.
这基本上告诉我们3-SAT是NP完全的。
And I can make a three-minute proof
我可以证明三分钟
that 3-SAT is NP-complete.
3-SAT是NP完全的。
Let's take that verifier guy that we have there.
让我们带一个在那里的验证者。
A verifier wants the input, which already have
验证者需要输入，该输入已经有
and the proof.
和证明。
Let's write the verifier as a circuit
让我们将验证器编写为电路
that takes the input and the proof as bits.
将输入和证明作为位。
Those are input to the circuit.
这些输入到电路。
The circuit is going to evaluate to true or false.
电路将评估为真或假。
Now that we have a circuit, it's easy to turn that
现在我们有了电路，现在很容易
into a logical expression.
转换成逻辑表达式
Turn AND gate and OR gate into-- and ANDs and ORs,
将AND门和OR门变成-和AND与OR，
and then reduce N-SAT to 3-SAT and get one of these.
然后将N-SAT还原为3-SAT并获得其中之一。
If you can solve 3-SAT, then you can
如果您可以解决3-SAT，那么您可以
compute values for the proof bits.
计算证明位的值。
Bam.
am
That's it.
而已。
So I take the verifier and I turn it into a circuit.
因此，我将验证器转换为电路。
The circuit is all logic gates.
该电路是所有逻辑门。
And then it has some inputs, the original problem input
然后有一些输入，原始问题输入
and the proof.
和证明。
These are represented as a series of bits,
这些被表示为一系列的位，
and they're all inputs in the circuit.
它们都是电路中的输入。
If the algorithm is polynomial time,
如果算法是多项式时间，
then the circuit also has to be polynomial in the input size.
那么电路的输入大小也必须是多项式。
Proof already has to be polynomial in the input size,
证明必须已经是输入大小的多项式，
so we're all good.
所以我们都很好。
We're all in polynomial world.
我们都在多项式世界中。
Now we take this circuit, and we turn it
现在我们把电路转过来
into a logical expression.
转换成逻辑表达式
Sorry not logical, logic, also known as a Boolean expression.
对不起没有逻辑，逻辑又称布尔表达式。
So the input bits become Boolean variables,
所以输入位变成布尔变量
and then we express gates as Boolean functions-- AND, OR,
然后我们将门表示为布尔函数-AND，OR，
NOT, whatever we want.
不，无论我们想要什么。
And this is going to give us some expression.
这将给我们一些表达。
That expression is going to map to N-SAT for some value of n.
该表达式将以n的某个值映射到N-SAT。
So then we're going to take this expression,
因此，我们将采用此表达式，
and we're going to reduce it to 3-SAT.
我们将其减少到3-SAT。
So actually we're going to reduce the expression to 3-CNF
所以实际上我们将表达式简化为3-CNF
and then run 3-SAT on it.
然后在其上运行3-SAT。
The expression will be reduced to 3-CNF.
该表达式将被简化为3-CNF。
So to something that looks like this,
所以对于这样的东西，
except you have three variables inside everything.
除了一切里面都有三个变量。
Once it's in 3-CNF, you can run 3-SAT on it.
一旦将其放入3-CNF中，就可以在其上运行3-SAT。
If it is satisfiable, then 3-SAT has
如果可以满足，则3-SAT具有
to give us some values here for the variables.
给我们一些变量值
Some of the variables are the problem input-- Sorry
有些变量是问题输入-对不起
the problem input gets hard coded in the circuit.
问题输入在电路中被硬编码。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Not thinking here-- hard coded in circuit,
不在这里思考-硬编码在电路中，
because we don't want it to tell us what the input is.
因为我们不希望它告诉我们输入的是什么。
And then the proof is encoded as a series
然后将证明编码为系列
of bits, which are inputs in the circuit.
位，是电路中的输入。
OK.
好。
So problem hard coded, proofs are inputs in the circuit.
因此问题经过硬编码，证明是电路中的输入。
We've taken the circuits, turned it into an input for 3-SAT.
我们采用了电路，将其转换为3-SAT的输入。
If 3-SAT says there is a valid variable assignment,
如果3-SAT表示存在有效的变量分配，
then that assignment tells me what the bits are in the proof.
然后那个作业告诉我证明中的位。
So that means I can take the proof, feed it to the verifier.
因此，这意味着我可以拿取证明，并将其提供给验证者。
The verifier will say it's happy,
验证者会说很高兴，
so we solved the problem.
所以我们解决了这个问题。
And this is true for any NP-complete problem.
这对于任何NP完全问题都是正确的。
NP-complete means it has to have a verifier that
NP完整意味着它必须具有一个验证程序
runs in polynomial time.
在多项式时间内运行。
So I have to be able to follow this process.
因此，我必须能够遵循此过程。
So for the factoring problem, for example, I
所以对于保理问题，例如，我
would take this modulo algorithm,
将采用这种取模算法
I would express it as a circuit.
我将其表示为电路。
The bits of P would be the input.
P的位将是输入。
I take that circuit and I turn into a 3-CNF formula, run it
我把电路变成一个3-CNF公式，运行它
on 3-SAT.
在3-SAT。
The variable values for which the circuit happy
电路满意的变量值
are the bits of P that make up.
是组成P的位。
So they're the bits of P. They make up a factor of n.
因此，它们是P的位。它们构成n的因数。
So if I can run 3-SAT fast enough to get an answer,
因此，如果我能够以足够快的速度运行3-SAT以获得答案，
then I have P and I have factor of n.
那么我有P，因子为n。
And I've become really, really rich, and bye guys, I'm gone.
而且我已经变得非常非常富有，再见了，我走了。
AUDIENCE: For each of those expressions,
听众：对于每个表达式，
you said you make that circuit n.
你说你做那个电路。
You've got all these inputs, which
您已经获得了所有这些输入，
are x1, x2, everything like that.
是x1，x2之类的东西。
Could you just go through every possible combination?
您能否进行所有可能的组合？
PROFESSOR: That's exponential, right?
教授：那是指数的，对不对？
That's two to the n, where n is number of variables.
那是n的2，其中n是变量数。
And the number of variables can be
并且变量的数量可以是
proportional to the number of terms.
与项数成正比。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
That would be fine with it.
这样就可以了。
PROFESSOR: So that means you have
教授：所以这意味着你有
an exponential running time.
指数运行时间。
It's not polynomial, which is reassuring,
这不是多项式，这让人放心，
because otherwise it would mean that the whole world has been
因为否则，这意味着整个世界
spinning their wheels around nothing all this time, right?
一直没有动静，对吧？
So it's reassuring that you can't
所以可以放心，您不能
find the solution in two minutes to this problem.
在两分钟内找到解决该问题的方法。
In fact, so far I've been trying to convince you
实际上，到目前为止，我一直在努力说服您
that you should not attempt to solve
你不应该试图解决
this problem in real time, so not on exam time,
这个问题是实时的，所以不是考试时间，
not on [INAUDIBLE] time, nor anywhere else where time
不在[听不清]时间，也没有其他时间
actually matters.
实际上很重要。
You guys bored?
你们无聊吗？
Maybe.
也许。
Well, so there's this proof that's
好吧，所以有这个证明是
not too hard to follow that says that if you solve 3-SAT
不太难的意思是，如果您解决了3-SAT
you have solved any NP-complete problem by turning
您已经解决了所有NP完全问题
the verifier into a logical expression.
验证程序转换为逻辑表达式。
That's what it comes down to.
这就是结果。
Now 2-SAT is polynomial.
现在2-SAT是多项式。
And if you guys want, we can go through the solution.
如果您愿意，我们可以提供解决方案。
If not, we can skip that.
如果没有，我们可以跳过。
But this tiny difference here, how many variables
但是这里的微小差异，有多少个变量
you're allowed inside, which looks
你被允许进入里面，看起来
like it might be a constant factor in an algorithm
就像它可能是算法中的常数
actually makes the difference between a very easy problem,
实际上使一个非常简单的问题有所不同，
a problem that's in P, and the hardest problem in NP.
P中的问题，NP中最困难的问题。
So 2-SAT is order n, so it's somewhere here.
所以2-SAT是n阶，所以在这里。
3-SAT is all the way here.
3-SAT一直在这里。
Small difference how many variables you're
小差异，您有多少个变量
allowed, two or three.
允许，两个或三个。
Makes all the difference in the world.
改变世界。
AUDIENCE: There are logic reductions you can make, right?
听众：您可以进行逻辑简化，对吗？
PROFESSOR: There are optimizations that you
教授：您有一些优化
can make.
可以使。
And there are some people who do research
有些人在做研究
on how to solve 3-SAT in a reasonably fast time.
如何在相当快的时间内解决3-SAT问题。
Because if you solve 3-SAT, any problem
因为如果您解决3-SAT问题
can be reduced to 3-SAT.
可以减少到3-SAT。
All right, we have a feeling that we're not going to be able
好吧，我们有种感觉，我们将无法
to solve this in polynomial time,
在多项式时间内解决这个问题
because a lot of people tried, but some researchers are hoping
因为很多人尝试过，但是一些研究人员希望
that well maybe you can solve 3-SAT in order of 2 to the n
好吧，也许您可​​以按2到n的顺序求解3-SAT
to the power of 0.00001, which exponential, right?
到0.00001的幂，哪个指数对？
But you can solve many problems with this.
但是您可以解决许多问题。
Active research, so far I don't think they've come very far.
积极的研究，到目前为止，我认为它们没有取得很大进展。
Actually, I shouldn't say that, because if you
其实我不应该这么说，因为如果你
apply the brute force algorithm, then
应用蛮力算法，然后
you die at about 20 variables.
你死于大约20个变量。
State of the art 3-SAT solving algorithms,
最先进的3-SAT求解算法，
I think it can handle 1,000 to 10,000 variables
我认为它可以处理1,000到10,000个变量
in a reasonable time, like a few hours.
在合理的时间内，例如几个小时。
There progress.
有进步。
And that is all by doing the reductions that you said.
这就是通过减少您所说的事情。
You see some optimizations that you can make in the expression.
您会看到可以在表达式中进行的一些优化。
You draw some inferences, and you
你得出一些推论，你
explore the possible configurations,
探索可能的配置，
taking us part way.
带我们一路走。
So there's a lot of active research going in that area
因此，在该领域有很多积极的研究
too.
太。
So far, they didn't get here.
到目前为止，他们还没有到达这里。
AUDIENCE: That's almost solving NP-complete problem then,
听众：那差不多解决了NP完全问题，
right?
对？
PROFESSOR: Well, yeah, the thing is
教授：是的，这是
in the end we care about practical solutions, right?
最后，我们关心实用的解决方案，对吗？
So they're hoping to get to a practical solution.
因此，他们希望找到一个切实可行的解决方案。
AUDIENCE: Well, a few hours is pretty practical.
听众：好吧，几个小时很实用。
So that's for some problems.
这就是一些问题。
Obviously they didn't solve factoring, right?
显然他们没有解决因数分解，对吗？
If they would have solved 1,000-bit factoring in a few
如果他们能在几个时间内解决1,000位分解
hours, then we would have noticed.
小时，那么我们会注意到的。
AUDIENCE: Maybe.
听众：也许吧。
Seriously, OK.
说真的，好的。
PROFESSOR: We would have noticed.
教授：我们会注意到的。
So far so good?
到现在为止还挺好？
Any questions on this stuff?
对这个东西有疑问吗？
So I want to reemphasize in two minutes, the reduction
所以我想在两分钟内重新强调
part of this.
部分。
So the reason why we can solve, once we solve
所以我们解决的原因
one NP-complete problem, we solve all the other ones
一个NP完全问题，我们解决所有其他问题
is reductions.
是减少。
So we've done a lot of graph transformations in this class.
因此，我们在此类中完成了许多图形转换。
We had three recitations and two or three exam problems on that,
在这方面，我们有3个背诵和2或3个考试题，
and I think we had some homework problems on it
我认为我们在作业上有一些问题
too-- a lot of graph transformations.
也是-很多图变换。
Graph transformations are just reductions.
图转换只是简化。
You take some problem that looks hard, and you do some magic,
您遇到一些看起来很难的问题，并且做了一些魔术，
and you build a graph that represents that problem,
然后您建立代表该问题的图表，
and you run shortest path on it.
并且您在其上运行最短路径。
Then you take the output for the shortest path algorithm,
然后将输出用于最短路径算法，
and you turn it into a solution to the initial problem.
然后将其变成最初问题的解决方案。
This means that we've reduced those problems
这意味着我们已经减少了这些问题
to shortest path.
最短的路径。
Well, you don't have to reduce to shortest path.
好吧，您不必减少到最短路径。
If you have a problem that you know how to solve,
如果您有知道如何解决的问题，
you can take any other problem and reduce to it,
您可以解决任何其他问题并将其减少，
and you've solved that other problem.
并且您已经解决了其他问题。
So basically, here, if you have your starting problem,
所以基本上，在这里，如果您遇到开始的问题，
shortest path is just one smiley face.
最短的路径只是一张笑脸。
As long as you arrive to any smiley face,
只要你到任何笑脸
you're in good shape.
您身体状况良好。
Of course, you have to be careful
当然要小心
that while you're doing you're reduction,
当你做的时候你在减少
your problem size doesn't explode.
您的问题规模不会爆炸。
So for example, if you take this problem-- if you take 3-SAT--
举例来说，如果您遇到这个问题-如果您使用3-SAT，
if you take a 3-CNF expression, and you reduce it
如果您使用3-CNF表达式并减少它
to the graph that has 3 to the n vertices,
到具有3到n个顶点的图，
and then you try to run [INAUDIBLE] on it,
然后尝试在其上运行[音频不清晰]，
it was the running time, 3 to the n.
这是运行时间，是3到n。
Now I've got a new polynomial, right?
现在我有了一个新的多项式，对吗？
So when you do the reductions, you
因此，当您进行减少操作时，
have to be careful about what happens to your input size.
必须注意输入大小会发生什么。
And that's about it.
就是这样。
This is complexity theory.
这就是复杂性理论。
It's basically one big excuse for why
这基本上是一个大借口
we can't solve some problems that are hard.
我们无法解决一些棘手的问题。